<Document>
  # Engagement with The Game
  ## LRP Limitations
  Powergaming, or playing with the goal of using the most optimal methods possible within the game to the exclusion of all other pursuits, is not appropriate in our MRP setting.  This is not a limitation on being a skilled player, but rather a limit on ignoring roleplay and deeper engagement with other players in favor of “winning”.

  [color=#a4885c]Unacceptable LRP behavior[/color]
  - Playing as a station engineer and refusing to allow other engineers to participate in setting up the engine while you create the most optimal setup possible.
  - Refusing to teach an intern to play chemistry because you are focused on creating full bags of chemicals as quickly as physically possible.
  - Expecting botanist characters to solely focus on growing the most optimal plants for medical and getting upset when they focus on any other aspect of botany.
  - In general, getting mad at other players for not following optimal methods in their gameplay of any role.
  - or the opposite, getting mad or giving up when other players are more skilled or knowledgeable at the game.

  ## HRP Limitations
  Roleplay is a major part of this server, but it is important to know that this is medium roleplay rather than high roleplay, there should be a balance between your focus on gameplay and your focus on roleplay. You should not focus on roleplay to the exclusion of other aspects of the game.
  - For example, spending an entire round bolted in a dorm room to play out a scene without engaging with your job or any aspect of the round outside of it.

  Engaging with roleplay is part of this game, but there is a limit on what is appropriate to portray. The goal of limiting HRP behavior is not to punish detailed roleplay, rather to limit the presence of elements that are especially upsetting or exclusive to other players.

  It is acceptable to behave seriously and roleplay out serious subject matter provided it is done with acceptance that this is primarily a comedic environment and with consideration for if it may be upsetting or triggering to those around you.

  Even within a comedic environment you are still obligated to behave appropriately and be sensitive to those around you. Making jokes at the expense of marginalized people is still [color=#994444]not acceptable[/color] per the rules of the server.

  ## The Law Of Funny
  If you are approaching these subjects with levity and a comedic tone then there is room for flexibility. However, tread lightly and be mindful of others.
  - A gray obsessed with a cigarette brand does not fall under realistic addiction roleplay.
  - Sobbing face down at the bar and cursing out Pun Pun because he spilled your favorite drink.
  - Spilling out a traumatic backstory that incorporates a detail which recontextualizes it in an absurd way. “My family died in a brutal crash with a clown shuttle and I've been depressed ever since. I've never seen so many dead clowns.”

  [color=#a4885c]Unacceptable HRP behavior[/color]
  - Realistic addiction roleplay
  - Habitually roleplaying drinking yourself to death or having a dependence on substances to function, including depiction of withdrawals and agitation when going without said substance.
  - Behaving aggressively towards other characters in order to obtain substances.
  Realistic depictions of suicidality and suicide
  - Roleplaying out despondency in response to the death of an in-character partner culminating in writing a note and committing suicide.
  - Realistic depictions of bigotry
  - For example, invoking real stereotypes surrounding minority groups while roleplaying conflict between characters.
  - It is also [color=#994444]unacceptable[/color] to roleplay fictional bigotry between characters.
  - Depictions of sexual trauma
  - For example, describing in detail abuse a character underwent in the past
  - Reacting to another character's actions as if they are done with the motivation to sexually harass or assault your character.
</Document>
