<Document>
  # Managing Your Out Of Character Emotions

  ## Distance Between IC actions and OOC emotions
  The actions taken between characters do not reflect out of character intent, it is important to maintain some distance between yourself and your character to have the best experience with the game.

  In character conflict does not reflect out of character conflict. If you are uncomfortable with an interaction, LOOC check-ins are the best method to diffuse potential tension. If issues persist or check-ins are not viable then press f1 to ahelp and contact admins to resolve the situation.

  Always assume those you interact with have good intentions and are there to have fun and enjoy the game with you. Projecting onto people that they are treating you with malice or the intent to ruin the game for you will always sour your experiences and overall make the game feel worse to play. This includes players you have had negative experiences with in the past, positive interactions can only begin in earnest when both of you allow it to. Always act in good faith and report bad actors to admins when issues arise.

  [color=#449944]Good:[/color]
  - You were killed by an antagonist, so you laugh about it and move on.
  - Security catches you as an antagonist, so you playfully taunt them or give an evil speech.
  - Someone in your department takes over a task you really wanted to do, so you ask if you can help them.
  - You're playing a rude character and want to establish two characters as disliking each other, so you message the other player to ask if they'd be okay with that.
  - Your body rots due to others overlooking it in a chaotic situation, so you accept the circumstances and move on.

  [color=#994444]Bad:[/color]
  - You were killed by an antagonist, so you take this as a personal insult and complain about them in deadchat.
  - Security catches you as an antagonist, so you yell at them, and call them shitsec over the radio.
  - Someone in your department takes over a task you really wanted to do, so you complain about them over the radio and refuse to interact with them.
  - You're playing a rude character, so you use that as an excuse to vent your OOC emotions and insult players for perceived slights.
  - Your body rots due to others overlooking it in a chaotic situation, so you take this as a sign that no one cares about you.

  ## Interruptions to Roleplay
  Interruptions are part of this game. You could be having a discussion where you disclose your dramatic past you've been building up to revealing over time when at any moment a wizard suddenly bursts in and kills you instantly. This is unavoidable and part of what makes this game so fun. It is important that you be open to this unpredictable nature and not be distressed and upset when it happens to you. Momentary emotions are part of life, but if you find yourself genuinely upset for extended periods when your roleplay is interrupted then you should take a break to cool down. If you have repeated difficulties recovering from being upset by in-game actions and events, it could better serve you to find a space where you can enjoy roleplay without the randomness and interruptions inherent to Space Station 14.

  Antagonists are crucial to this game. As wonderful as it is when roleplay with an antagonist goes well, there is nothing wrong with getting snuck up on and killed suddenly. You are not always owed a full scene with an antagonist before you die to them, and if you find yourself feeling enraged or distraught when an antagonist kills or otherwise executes their goals relating to your character, you would likely be more comfortable roleplaying in another medium.

  ## Playing to Win
  Space Station 14 is a game with no win state and should be approached as such. All should keep in mind that whatever your goal may be in a round they are secondary to keeping the round moving and having fun.
  - Antagonists should keep in mind that the goals given to them by the game are more like prompts than direct objectives. They should make an attempt to complete them but are not strictly required to do so. An antagonist who achieves none of their goals while creating an interesting and fun round dynamic with their tools and freedom is no less successful than an antagonist who achieves each goal set for them.
  - Antagonists should not utilize powergaming to achieve their goals. Hyper efficient plans with minimal risk are not engaging or particularly interesting for other players. As an antagonist you have more control over the pace and direction of the round, this does not make you the main character of the station.
  - Unless it is explicitly your objective, living through the round is not success. Reaching CentComm is not the primary goal of the crew and you should engage as much as possible with the ongoing round. Making the decision to attempt escape or the decision to escalate with antagonists and to save yourself or others' lives are both equally compelling narratives to roleplay through as long as you are active and engaged in the events.
</Document>
