<Document>
# Topicals

When tending to external wounds, topical medications should be your first port of call.
These can be used to stop bleeding, or to augment the speed at which wounds heal naturally.

## Brutes

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Brutepack" />
</Box>

A bruise pack can bandage and tend to all types of brute injuries at a moderate level.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicatedSuture" />
</Box>

A medicated suture can bandage and tend to all types of brute injuries.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Gauze" />
</Box>

Gauze can bandage and tend to lacerations and punctures, but is most effective on puncture wounds.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SimpleSuture" />
</Box>

A simple suture can bandage and tend to lacerations and punctures, but is most effective on lacerations.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ElectrodePad" />
</Box>

An electrode pad can tend to bruises, and offers minor assistance to respiration.

## Burns

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ointment" />
</Box>

Ointment can tend to burns of all types, but is less effective against caustic burns.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RegenerativeMesh" />
</Box>

Regenerative meshes can tend burns of all types, including caustic burns.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AloeCream" />
</Box>

Aloe cream can effectively tend to heat burns.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShockGel" />
</Box>

Shock gel can tend to electric and heat burns, but is most effective on electric burns.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EZGraft" />
</Box>

EZ graft can effectively tend to caustic burns, but causes lacerations in the process of doing so.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ColdPack" />
</Box>

Cold packs can effectively tend to cold burns.

## Other

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Tincture" />
</Box>

Tincture can tend to any type of wound, but weakly.

</Document>

<!--
  This Source Code Form is subject to the terms of the Mozilla Public
  License, v. 2.0. If a copy of the MPL was not distributed with this
  file, You can obtain one at http://mozilla.org/MPL/2.0/.
-->
