<Document>
  # The Escalation Cheat Sheet

  Generally, per Server Rules, it's discouraged to hunt down or 'validhunt' people who you suspect may be antagonists based on OOC knowledge. Escalation rules specifically exist to facilitate hostile interactions between antagonists and non-antagonists, while accounting for the disconnect between OOC and IC knowledge. However, escalation can also apply to interactions between non-antagonists. In addition, some antagonists inherently have lethal intent, and as such some escalation rules may be skipped when interacting with them. It can get confusing.

  This table isn't a be-all end-all to escalation, but it aims to answer common questions players might have about the appropriate steps to follow when certain situations occur.

  Escalation is graded on a basis of lethality. The general scale goes verbal - nonlethal (stun batons, unarmed shoves, etc.) - harmful (anything that does damage) - lethal (the distinction between punching someone once or twice versus attacking them into crit) - round removal. Depending on the situation, this scale might not be completely applicable, but it's the foundational guideline for these interactions.

  When interacting with someone, consider what level of lethality they are engaging with you at. This might change over time - someone trying to approach you with lethal intent might fall into crit, at which point they are no longer a threat, and can be de-escalated against by getting them medical treatment. Similarly, a person firing off a single warning shot doesn't have the same intent as someone engaged in an active firefight. Take the other player's intentions into account, and work together to tell an engaging story.

  As a note, non-antagonists should not be seeking to round remove anyone in any cases other than extreme circumstances.

  If you have any concerns about whether a course of action follows the rules of escalation, reach out to administrators via AHelp. You may also choose to check in with scene partners using the LOOC channel to make sure other players consent to actions which sidestep traditional escalation rules. Communication is key to healthy roleplay!

  The following scenarios assume you are a non-antagonist.
  <Table Columns="3">
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Center" VerticalAlignment="Stretch">
        Scenario
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Center" VerticalAlignment="Stretch">
        Appropriate Escalation Example
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Center" VerticalAlignment="Stretch">
        Notes
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        A clown steals your shoes.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Steal something back, or call security.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Someone hops the counter to your department.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Yell at them, shove them until they leave, or call security.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Punching and shoving are not the same thing.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Someone hops the counter to your department and doesn't leave.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Okay now you can start punching them.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Opt for nonlethal submission if possible (disablers, flashes) first!
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Someone punches you.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Punch them back.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        If they go into crit, take them to medical!
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        As an officer, someone does a minor, non-lethal crime in front of you.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Whistle at them, yell at them, tell them to stop.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Escalate to stuns only AFTER attempting verbal escalation.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Someone shoots you with a gun.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Shoot them back, run away, or call security.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        If they go into crit, take them to medical!
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Someone starts attacking another person in front of you.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Call security, run away, attempt to drag away or disarm the attacker, or yell at the attacker.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        If security doesn't show up, or it's clear that the intent is lethal, you MAY choose to attack this person yourself, but remember that your character likely fears death!
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        As an engineer, multiple people insult you over greencomms.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Remove the key from the greencomms teleserver.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Some salvagers cause multiple problems for you over the course of a round.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Steal the salvage magnet.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        A player-controlled spider walks into a room.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Kill the spider.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Players aren't obligated to follow escalation rules for non-pet animals like vent creatures.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        A Heretic draws a transmutation sigil in front of you.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Give some verbal reaction, run away, or call for a coworker.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Depending on the flow of the round, your character may not be aware of the nature of a heretic circle. Until lethal intent is declared, respond in kind!
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        A Heretic draws a transmutation sigil in front of you and pulls out a knife.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Okay now you can start punching them.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        If they go into crit, take them to medical!
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        You see a Heretic who has ascended.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Call security, run away, or engage with them lethally at your own risk.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Once a Heretic has announced their ascension, they can be assumed to be operating at lethal intent...
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        An ascended Heretic approaches you and begins to talk to you.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Call security, run away, or engage in the conversation.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        ...But, when your scene partner deescalates, you should do the same thing.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        You see someone you suspect to be a Head Revolutionary flash another crewmember.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Report the incident to security, or run away.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        You see someone you suspect to be a Head Revolutionary in a round where the presence of Revolutionaries is known, and you are mindshielded.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Engage the Head Revolutionary in combat until they are no longer an immediate threat.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        All mindshielded crewmembers may take steps to neutralise Head Revolutionaries once their existence is confirmed.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        You see an invisible shimmer which you suspect to be a Ninja.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        React to the presence of an invisible 'something', and attempt to investigate it.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
    </ColorBox>
    <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        An invisible shimmer throws a shuriken at you.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
        <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Stab the invisible shimmer.
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
        <ColorBox>
      <Box HorizontalAlignment="Left" VerticalAlignment="Stretch" Margin="10">
        Try to play in the space a little where you can. If you get attacked, though, all bets are off!
      </Box>
    </ColorBox>
  </Table>
</Document>
